NICHOLAS GOUDEAU

ngoudeau2012@gmail.com / (832) 338-0385 / https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicholasgoudeau/

SUMMARY:

Self-motivated tech professional with a background in people development, performance management and customer service currently transitioning into a Web Development career. I'm extremely excited to bring my intrapersonal skills into the realm of Web Development and create products that result in the best customer experience possible.

EDUCATION:

Full-stack development certification – Trilogy Education, August 2020

Certified in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and Node.js

Bachelor of Science and Arts - Double Major in Finance and Economics, The University of Texas at Dallas, May 2016

- Cumulative GPA 3.76/4.0 | Major GPA 3.88/4.0
- Dean's List 6 semesters

EXPERIENCE:

June 2017 – October 2019: Enjoy Technology, Inc. – Seattle, WA Area Manager

- Established and managed the Seattle Market for Enjoy, end to end responsibility for hiring, developing, training, and coaching sales associates
- Grew and developed sales team by 240% in four months while showing five to ten percent month over month growth in revenue
- Coached a sales team of seventeen through a major culture shift to sales and grew sales revenue sixty-five percent over the course four months
- Created gap analysis tools to help break down raw sales data for direct reports resulting in 100% sales increase for lower performers
- Achieved a forty percent solution success rate, over the company average of thirty- five percent
- Worked alongside PMs and Engineers to understand and act on customer feedback to increase customer satisfaction by fifteen NPS

July 2016 – June 2017: Enjoy Technology, Inc. – Houston, TX Customer Experience Expert

- Quickly mastered and trained other Experience Experts in all of the products and solutions offered by Enjoy and our partners
- Leveraged product knowledge and customer connections to deliver over 300 Enjoy Experiences while leading team in sales and customer service rating
- Mastered identifying customer needs/problems and positioning solution products to ensure the customer was set up for success resulting in sales for the company
- Developed "Product Cheat Sheets" as a learning resource to help Experts retain product knowledge
- Collaborated and led other sales associates to ensure that the team was constantly sharing best practices
 resulting in the market leading the company in sale and customer service rating
- Continuously provided feedback to leadership on the mobile retail experience we have developed at Enjoy

June 2015 – August 2015: New York Life - AARP Program Program Analyst Intern

- Collaborated with various devisions to obtain sales data and analyze the new marketing material's impact on performance
- Provided key metrics and analyzed raw data to increase from 6M to 25M recurring life premiums over the next three years and presented the growth plan to Executives of the company

NICHOLAS GOUDEAU

Page 2

 Built and managed an excel model to track marketing materials usage in the field, which allowed us to reduce our marketing bandwidth to focus budgeting and production on effective products

SKILLS:

- Critical Thinking (Advance)
- Statistical Analysis
- Customer Service (Master)
- Investment Analysis
- Excel (Intermediate)

- Problem Solving (Advanced)
- Sales Force (Skilled)
- Facilitation (Advanced)
- Big Data

ACADEMIC PROJECTS:

Econometrics (August 2015 – December 2015)

- Gained insight on how to retrieve, analyze, and apply economic meaning to big data through statistical analysis
- Assigned a project, and was responsible for establishing the metrics, analyzing, and forming a conclusion on whether or not Southwest Airline's Revenue was correlated to the price of oil
- Gained experience in statistical analysis programs Eviews and Stata
- Gained experience in working with big data using Microsoft Excel

Analyst, Investment Management (August 2015 – December 2015)

- Worked on a team of investment analysis for The University of Texas at Dallas' investment fund
- Became one of four analysis to oversee the fund's tech sector holdings
- Led a team of four to create a business valuation model and presentation on Adobe and Apple to come up with a buy, sell, or hold option for the two holdings
- Researched, studied, and analyzed Facebook Inc. Then successfully pitched a buy strategy to swap Facebook
 Inc. into the fund to replace a lower performing stock
- Gained insight on how to gather data, analyze strategic moves, create and present business valuations to pitch to investors of the fund